Inventory of the Paul B. Ryan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- First Line of Defense Research Materials File, 1882-1986
  - Department of Defense, 1973-1984
    - Reports, 1978-1981
      - 1978 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - 1979 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - 1980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - 1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Senior officials' biographies, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Telephone directories, 1973-1984 (Box 41)
    - Under Secretary of the Navy Woolsey on Pentagon analysts, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Foreign relations, 1919-1925, 1967, 1970-1985
    - ANZUS problem, 1984-1985 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Bases, 1976-1980 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Caribbean problems for USN, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Carter and foreign policy, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Carter's diplomacy, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 5-7)
    - Carter's foreign policy, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - CENTO pact, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Falklands War, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Helsinki agreement, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Marines to Persian Gulf, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - NATO and Eastern Front War, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - NATO and the Navy, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Overview of US foreign policy, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Role of USN in combatting terrorism, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - SALT II ( AEI News Digest), 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - SALT II, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - SALT II, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - SALT II, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - SALT II, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sea lanes, Indian Ocean, 1972-1980 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Soviets, 1970, 1973-1984
      - Admiral Moorer on Soviet aims, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Admiral T.H. Moorer on Soviet aims, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - Carter and USSR, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Collins and Chwat, "US-Soviet Military Balance,", 1976 (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - Comparison of USN and USSR defense, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Congressional background on Soviets, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Congressman Aspin on Soviets, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - Cuban-Soviet threat to South Atlantic, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Detente [Soviets], 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Detente [Soviets], 1978 (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Erickson, the Soviet military, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Maps of the USSR, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - McConnell on Gryshkov, Russian Navy, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Military balance, US vs. USSR, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Mission of the Soviet Navy, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Net assessment of USN and USSR Navies, circa 1975 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Problems of the Kremlin, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Rand study, "Divergent US-USSR Military Expenditures,", 1979 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Senator Sam Nunn and NATO, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        "NATO and the New Soviet Threat," Report of Senator Sam Nunn to the Committee on Armed Services, United States, Senate.
      - Senator Stone of FL on Soviet bases in Cuba, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Soviet bases in Cuba, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Soviet military policy and Soviet Navy, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Soviet naval strategy, 1970, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Soviet naval strength, 1974, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Soviet Navy, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Soviet Navy, 1980-1984 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Soviet Navy and forward deployment/naval power in Soviet policy, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Soviet Navy in Vietnamese ports, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Soviet Navy trend upward, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Soviet oil crunch, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Soviet risk-taking, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Soviet theater strategy, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Soviet threat to NATO, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Soviet Union and its problems, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Soviet vs. US defense strategists, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Soviets in the Caribbean and Latin America, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Soviets in the Caribbean, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Soviets in Cuba, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Soviets in the Middle East, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Soviets' views on USN and defense, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Swedish report on Soviet submarine activity, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - "United States/Soviet Military Balance: A Frame of Reference for Congress," for use of the Senate Committee on Armed Services, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - US/USSR Armed Forces compared, 1977-1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - US-USSR confrontation, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - US-USSR in the Far East, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - USN and Soviet Navy in Far East and Indian Ocean, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - USN and USSR anti-submarine warfare, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - What motivates Moscow, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Terrorism, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Trilateral Commission, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Trilateral Commission, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - US and Afghanistan, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - US and Africa, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - US and Africa, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - US and China, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - US and Latin America, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - US and Middle East, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - US and OPEC, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - US and Taiwan, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - US and the UN, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - US bases abroad, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - US foreign bases, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - US-Japanese defense, 1982-1984 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - US-NATO policy, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - USN and Afghanistan, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - USN and Iran, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - USN and Iran, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 19)
      Per remainder of folder title: "Capture of U.S. Embassy in Iran, death of U.S. Ambassador Dubs in Kabul."
    - USN and Japan, 1978-1980 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - USN and Japan, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - USN and Japanese defense forces, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - USN and Kenya, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - USN and NATO, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 8, Box 23, Folder 7)
    - USN and NATO, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - USN and OPEC, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - USN and refugees ("boat people"), 1978 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - USN and strategic raw materials from abroad, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - USN in Indian Ocean, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - USN in the Far East, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - USN in the Mediterranean, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - USN in the Middle East, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 2, Box 21, Folder 12)
    - USN in Turkish waters, 1919-1924 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - USN in Turkish waters, 1925 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - USN investigation of Beirut terror killings, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - General research material, 1959, 1972-1985
    - Bibliography, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Imperial War Museum, Department of Printed Books, accessions list PF 78, undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Map, undated (Box 26, Folder 32)
      Azimuthal Equidistant Projection Centered on Clark Air Base.
    - Maps, notes and documents, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Material for First Line of Defense, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Questions for interview with SECNAV, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Research documents on US military, 1972-1983 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Research material for First Line of Defense, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Research plan for book [ First Line of Defense], 1978 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Scandals" in Washington, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Individuals, 1923, 1942-1986
    - Admiral Arleigh Burke and Bay of Pigs, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
    - Admiral Gorshkov (USSR) bio data, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Admiral Hayward, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Admiral Hayward, Chief of Naval Operations, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Admiral Hayward statements, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Admiral Holloway, Chief of Naval Operations report, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Admiral Long, CINCPAC interview, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Admiral T. Moorer, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Admiral A.M. Pride, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Admiral Radford (Ike's Chairman, JCS) bio data, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Admiral Rickover, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Admiral Rickover viewpoint, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Admiral Sagerholm speech, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Admiral Sharp, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Admiral Stockdale, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Admiral Zumwalt statements, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Admiral Zumwalt statements, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Assistant Secretary of Defense Russell Murray, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Zbigniew Brzezinski in White House, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Carter, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Carter and defense, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Carter and leadership, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - CNO James Watkins, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - CNO Watkins speeches, 1983-1985 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Commander Richard Stratton, USN interview, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Eisenhower and "New Look" in Defense, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - General James Doolittle, USAAF documents, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - General James "Jimmy" Doolittle and Tokyo Raid, 1942-1983 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - General Doolittle, 1983-1985 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Edward Jayne of OMB [Office of Management and Budget], 1978 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Henry Kissinger, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Henry Kissinger clippings, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Kissinger and limited war, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Kissinger's ground design, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Arthur Knock on JFK, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Marine Corps Commandant Louis Wilson's statement to Congress, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Presidential candidate Reagan, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Ronald Reagan, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Ronald Reagan, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Ronald Reagan clippings, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - SECDEF Brown, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - SECDEF Harold Brown profile, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - SECDEF Harold Brown and his problems, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - SECDEF Brown and JCS Chairman Jones, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - SECDEF Donald Rumsfeld, 1975-1977 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - SECDEF James Schlesinger, 1974-1978 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - SECNAV Claytor biographical data, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - SECNAV Graham Claytor statements, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - SECNAV Claytor, Vice Admiral Stockdale, Admiral Hayward bio sketches, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - SECNAV Hidalgo, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - SECNAV Lehman bio, 1981-1988 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - SECNAV Lehman, documents by, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - SECNAV Lehman documents, 1985-1986 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - SECNAV McNaughton background, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - SECNAV Woolsey biographical data, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Senator Boyd and Speaker O'Neill on defense, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Senator Moynihan, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Senator Moynihan, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Senator Moynihan file, 1978-1980 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Vice Admiral Crowe in Persian Gulf, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Vice Admiral Kidd, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Vice Admiral Long, UCNO, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Vice Admiral Gerald Miller speeches, 1973-1979 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Vice Admiral G.E. Miller, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Vice Admiral Miller, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Vice Admiral J.P. Moorer, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Vice Admiral Stockdale, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Vice President Mondale clipping, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Vice President Mondale's mission to China, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Biographical sketches of USN officers in Turkey, 1923 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Biography of CNO, 1943-1978 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - SECDEF/CNO posture statement, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - USN Admirals' public statements, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Other military, 1974, 1978-1981, 1984-1985
    - Decline of US Armed Forces, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Merchant Marines, 1978-1981, 1984-1985
      - Decline in US merchant ships, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Decline of US Merchant Marine, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Documents on US Merchant Marine, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Foreign Merchant Marines, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - US Merchant Marine, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Waning US Merchant Marine, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - US Congress as military officers - reserve, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - US Marines in 20th century, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Policies, 1976-1981
    - Carter and defense policy, 1977-1980 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Containment policy, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Human rights and US security, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - JCS and national security policy, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Shaping military policy, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - US arms control policy, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - US military posture, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - US national security and news media, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Printed matter, 1920, 1949-1951, 1957-1985
    - Newsweek clippings, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - The Retired Officer Journal clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Seapower, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Time articles on Navy, 1950, 1957, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - U.S. News and World Report clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - "CNO Report," US Navy, FY 1979, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - "Commander's Estimate of the Situation,", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "Navy Gun Systems: 'Alive and Well,'" James L. George, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Naval Power as an Investment of U.S. Foreign Policy," John M. Tierney, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Naval Watch in the Mideast," George W. Henderson with Paul B. Ryan, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - "The U.S. Navy," Bruce Powers, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Article by Krepon on Naval air power, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      "A Navy to Match National Purposes," Michael Krepon.
    - Article by Soviet Admiral Gorshkov, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Articles [defense and strategy], 1975-1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Congressional study, anti-submarine war, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Essays on Grenada and Pueblo Affair, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Japan, white paper on defense [Soviets], 1979 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Journal articles on strategy and defense, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Journal articles on strategy and defense, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Military studies on seapower and naval warfare, 1949, 1962-1966, 1970-1979 (Box 10)
      - B-36 bomber testimony from naval officials before US House of Representatives, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - "The Balanced Fleet - Weapons System for Limited War,", 1962 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - "Control of the Sea - Lost by Default?,", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - "Influence of Sea Power on the Cold War,", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - "The Influence of Threat and Alliance Setting on National Defense Expenditures,", 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - "The Limitation of Naval General Purpose Forces in Historical Perspective,", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - "Long Range Future of the Navy, Phase I Vol. I,", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Long Range Future of the Navy, Phase I Vol. II,", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "Long Range Future of the Navy, Phase II Vol. I,", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - "Long Range Future of the Navy, Phase II Vol. II,", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "Maritime Strategy as Applied to Limited War,", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - "National Sea Power: An Evolution of National Strategy, ", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "On National Strategy: The Search for Usable Power,", 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - "Naval Strategy in the Nuclear Era,", 1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - "The Navy's Role in U.S. Military Deterrent Forces,", 1962 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Potential for confrontation in the Indian Ocean, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "The Role of Seapower During Arms Control,", 1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - "The Role of the Navy as an Element of National Strategy,", 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - "The Role of the U.S. Navy in Diplomacy,", 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - SALT under Carter Administration, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "Sea Power Strategy for the Late Sixties,", 1963 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - "The Significance of Divergent U.S./USSR Military Expenditures,", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - US naval power in the Mediterranean, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - "US Navy and US Marine Corps as Instruments of Foreign Policy,", 1965 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - US/Soviet presence in the Indian Ocean, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - NSC-100, Symington report on "Grave World Situation,", 1951 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Papers on US defense, undated (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Pentagon clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Pressure groups, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Pressure groups, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Pressure groups, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      May 1980 issue of Insider: Report of the Coalition for Peace Through Strength.
    - Printed materials, 1968-1976 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Printed materials, 1981-1985 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Printed materials, 1982-1985 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Printed materials and documents from USN, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Publications, 1961-1964 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
    - SECNAV report, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Stanford ROTC news, 1981-1982 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Public opinion, 1948-1980
    - Carter and public opinion, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Defense and US public opinion, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - How U.S. allies view us, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Mood of America, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Mood of the country re USN, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Public attitude toward defense, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Public opinion polls on defense, 1948-1978 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - US public opinion and defense, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - US public opinion and defense, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Recruiting, 1946-1985
    - The draft, 1979-1980
      - Draft vs. volunteer force, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - The draft, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Draft, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Conscription, the draft, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Women in the military, 1983-1985 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Women in the Navy, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Women in the Navy, 1946-1980 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Women in the Navy, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - USN manpower problems in the 1970s, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - USN personnel problem, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - USN recruiting problem, 1973-1982 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Naval strategy and leadership, 1941, 1971-1985
    - Admiral Bagley on sea power, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Admiral E.J. King and command philosophy, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Center for Naval Warfare maritime strategy, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Command" by consensus (whiz kids), 1973 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Future of the Navy, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Law of Sea, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Law of Sea (mining), 1980 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Naval leadership, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Naval leadership vs. Carter, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Naval strategy, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Navy Readiness Doctrine, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Problems in naval leadership, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Rapid development force, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Sea Plan 2000, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Library computer search on Navy and sea power, printout, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Taft and Hart on sea power, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - US naval strategy papers, 1971-1984 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - US sea power philosophy in 1970s, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - USN in 1956, nuclear navy, undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - USN strategic documents, 1973-1985 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Vice Admiral Stockdale on leadership, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - US Navy (USN) general, 1882-1986
    - Developments in the US Navy, 1985-1986 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Diego Garcia Navy Base, 1965-1972, 1975-1982
      - Articles, 1975-1982 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - British Navy history of Diego Garcia, copy of unpublished manuscript, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Maps and government documents, 1965-1972 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Documents and reports on USN action, 1882-1943 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - History of the US Navy, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Letter from Admiral Bristol to Commander, USN Forces Europe, 1923 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Letter from Admiral Bristol to SECNAV, 1923 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Naval War College, 1934, 1978-1979
      - Naval War College Conference, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Reports on Naval War College Conferences, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Helmut Sonnenfeldt at Naval War College, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Speech at Naval War College [Rear Admiral McNamec], 1934 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Research documents on Navy, 1976-1985 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - USN correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - USN documents, 1959-1961 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - USN documents, stores, and correspondence, 1931-1977 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - USN grooming standards, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - USN in 1970s, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - USN in 1980s, 1982-1984 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - USN in 1980s, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - USN info and documents, 1980-1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - USNA curriculum, 1972-1973 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - US Navy (USN) issues, 1959, 1962-1981
    - Alleged US naval wastage by public forums, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Bribery in the USN, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Decline of the USN, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Decline of US technology and defense, 1975, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - "Mayday" for the Mayaguez, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - USN decline in research, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - USN vs. system analysts in Pentagon, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - USS Constellation investigations, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 4-6)
    - USS Kitty Hawk mutiny, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - USS Liberty, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - USS Liberty incident, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - USS Stone County investigation, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Vessels and weaponry, 1962-1981
      - Carrier debate, 1966-1978 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Carter and the nuclear carrier, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Carter and the nuclear carrier, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Congress, shipbuilding, and defense, 1974-1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Controversy on Navy shipbuilding, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - Cruise missile and the USN, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Definition-descriptions of US Navy aircraft and missiles, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Description of USN weapons systems: Aegis, Poseidon, Polaris, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Fact brochure on Polaris and Poseidon weapons system, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Glossary of USN ships, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Hi-low (large ships-small ships?), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - MX missile issue, 1963-1981 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - MX missile vs. small submarines, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Nature of naval power, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Naval aircraft gap, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 18)